Dennis Littlefield

Littlefield.Dennis@Outlook.com | (437) 248-6759 | Toronto, Ontario



LinkedIn: https://ca.linkedin.com/in/dennislittlefield

| GitHub: https://github.com/DLittlefield81/

| **Profile:** https://dlittlefield81.github.io/DennisLittlefieldPortfolio/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer leveraging over 20 years of customer service, problem-solving, and critical thinking background. Currently working on a certificate as a Full Stack Developer from the University of Toronto Bootcamp, with newly developed skills in JavaScript, NodeJS, and ExpressJS. Experienced in optimizing productivity, efficiency and service quality across various environments.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, PHP, JavaScript, ES6+, JQuery, SQL, NoSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Node^{JS}, React^{JS}, Express^{JS}, Bootstrap, GitHub, Heroku, WordPress CMS, Video Editing, MS Office

PROFESSIONAL PORTFOLIO

FlytCheckr

https://github.com/DLittlefield81/FlytCheckr | https://dlittlefield81.github.io/FlytCheckr/

Summary: Utilized Amadeus API to fetch flight data. The user selects origin,

destination, and date a fare matrix is provided.

Role: Team Development

Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Amadeus API

Dennis Littlefield Portfolio

https://github.com/DLittlefield81/DennisLittlefieldPortfolio | https://dlittlefield81.github.io/DennisLittlefieldPortfolio/

Summary: Professional portfolio as a developer

Role: Sole Developer Tools: HTML, CSS

Dennis Littlefield

<u>Littlefield.Dennis@Outlook.com</u> | (437) 248-6759 | Toronto, Ontario

EDUCATION

Full Stack Developer Bootcamp University of Toronto

Toronto, Ontario, Canada • 2022

Computer Programmer Analyst Lambton College

Sarnia, Ontario, Canada • 2001-2002

WORK HISTORY

Web Developer

Freelance

Toronto, ON • 2011 - Current

- Develop websites for clients to their specifications while ensuring a consistent look and visual theme across the website by promoting uniform fonts, formatting, images, and layout.
- Successfully identified, diagnosed, and fixed website problems, including broken links, typographical errors, and formatting issues
- Continually reinforce industry best practices.

Communication Operator

VIA Rail Canada Inc.

Toronto, ON • 2001 - Current

- Coordinate multiple teams to ensure daily operations, and on-time performance metrics are met.
- Upon equipment failures, assisted teams to redirect passengers to alternate routes to ensure on-time departures.
- Assisted in app development for staff duty scheduling and provided testing feedback to the development team.
- Coordinated construction of a parade float and procured driver and trailer for the event.